sait.ca 2019-06-29

# Privacy Policies | SAIT, Calgary, Canada

## SAIT's compliance with anti-spam legislation

SAIT complies with new federal legislation for the sending of electronic messages. Canada's anti-spam legislation (CASL) regulates the sending of commercial electronic messages, including email, text, social media, advertising and cellphone communications that encourage participation in a commercial activity.

Learn more about Canada's anti-spam legislation on our [FAQ](https://www.sait.ca/about-sait/administration/privacy-policies/canadian-anti-spam-legislation) page.

## Personal information

At SAIT, we intend to give you as much control as possible over your personal information. In general, you can visit SAIT on the web without telling us who you are or revealing any information about yourself. There are times, however, when we may need information from you, such as your name and address. It is our intent to let you know before we collect personal information from you on the internet.

If you choose to give us personal information via the internet that we or our educational partners may need — to correspond with you, process an order or provide you with a subscription, for example — it is our intent to let you know how we will use such information. If you tell us that you do not wish to have this information used as a basis for further contact with you, we will respect your wishes. We do keep track of the domains from which people visit us. We analyze this data for trends and statistics, and then we discard it.

We have implemented these practices for the SAIT home page ([sait.ca](https://www.sait.ca/).) We are also instructing our employees to include information on privacy practices everywhere information is collected on the SAIT web, tailored to what that portion of the site does and reflecting the practices outlined here.

## Application information

The personal information you provide on the application form is collected under the authority of the [Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act](https://www.servicealberta.ca/foip/) of the Province of Alberta, Section 33(c), the Statistics Act (Canada), and the Taxation Act (Canada). It will be used to determine your eligibility for admission to program(s)/course(s) of studies at SAIT, to facilitate your enrolment, to contact you regarding SAIT programs and services, to administer and evaluate institute programs/courses, and for statistical purposes. It will form part of your record as an applicant and alumnus and will be disclosed to academic and administrative units at SAIT and to Statistics Canada and Alberta Enterprise and Advanced Education for statistical, funding, planning, and market research purposes, and to the Students' Association of SAIT and the SAIT Alumni Association for contact purposes and membership services. This information will also be maintained in a mailing list for direct marketing purposes, market research surveys or the distribution of other promotional material as approved by the Office of the Registrar. Your personal information is protected by Alberta's [Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act](https://www.servicealberta.ca/foip/) and can be reviewed on request. If you have any questions about the collection or use of this information, contact the FOIP Coordinator at 403.284.8748.

## Business relationships

The SAIT site contains links to other websites. SAIT is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites.

## Online privacy statement

Many organizations, including SAIT, collect visitor information from their interaction with that organization's website. For SAIT, that information is generated through the use of **cookies** and/or information gathered from submitting **online forms and online chat**.

Organizations evaluating visitor behaviour specific to that organization's website has become an integral and accepted part to enhance today's web browsing experience.

As a publicly funded and publicly accountable institution, SAIT is legally mandated to comply with Alberta's [Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act](https://www.servicealberta.ca/foip/) (FOIPP) as it relates to visitor information.

SAIT protects the privacy of visitor information gathered. It also advocates transparency as to how that information is collected.

### How does SAIT use visitor information?

SAIT uses visitor information gathered from its websites in the following ways:

  * Improve visitor experience online with SAIT's websites, email correspondence, or SAIT's social media platforms
  * Measure the performance of advertising campaigns
  * Improve the content structure and information architecture of the website
  * Analyze when its websites are used to determine key messaging times
  * Enhance SAIT's marketing and communications efforts, through customer relationship modelling, with prospective and established students, customers, partners and clients
  * Interpret information gathered to tweak and improve SAIT's services, products, courses, and program offerings

Cookies

A cookie is a packet of data that a website can send to your browser (E.G.: Google Chrome, Mozilla Firefox, Internet Explorer, etc.) which may then store it on your system. This information, which includes session information and personal preferences, is then used by that website — in this case, SAIT — to effectively deliver pages to you with personalized information and settings tailored to meet your specific needs when you return to that website.

Visitor information, via the use of cookies, is collected on an aggregate basis and is not personally identifiable to your individual use or our site.

All visitors, through their browser, have the ability to manage their cookies. SAIT strongly believes in empowering visitors of our site. If you would like to manage or disable the use of cookies, please determine the browser(s) you are using. We have provided links to the top 3 browsers for managing and disabling your cookies.

Online Forms and Online Chat

Online forms and online chat are utilities in which visitors can directly engage with the staff of that organization.

SAIT uses online forms and online chat to empower visitors, through the information provided by the visitor, with the ability to, among other things:

  * Ask a question(s)/request more information
  * Join an email list
  * Register for a program, course or event
  * Book a SAIT facility or resource
  * Provide a calculation
  * Request contact from SAIT regarding a specific service
  * Create visitor customized content

Online forms and online chat frequently require visitor contact information, as well as other necessary information, before that utility can be used to contact SAIT.

#### Online Forms

Information inputted by visitors into SAIT forms submitted from SAIT’s websites either generate an email to designated-SAIT staff with that information or are fed into a database accessible only to designated-SAIT staff.

Primarily, visitor submitted information via forms is used by SAIT to complete the immediate goal of that form (IE: registration).

Additionally, the time and content submitted by a visitor may be used by SAIT to create subsequent customized customer relationship messaging sent to and tailored to that visitor. The ability to unsubscribe is always provided for scheduled email correspondence as registered through a SAIT form.

#### Online Chat

Online chat allows visitors to interact in real-time with designated SAIT staff during designated hours. During off-hours, visitors have the ability to send information or ask a question of designated SAIT staff to address the following business day(s).

Primarily, visitor submitted information via online chat is used by SAIT to address the immediate needs of that specific visitor.

Additionally, visitor information submitted via SAIT online chat is used to enhance website content and make it more informative to visitors of SAIT’s websites.

If you require any information please contact [webmaster@sait.ca](mailto:webmaster@sait.ca).
